<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memoirs</title>
    <description>Welcome to Memoirs</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:25:31 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:25:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Coffee can change your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;His mobile phone beeped. He immediately picked up the mobile to reply. He knew who the message is from. Its Kaveri. “Why is she not taking any step further? Does she really like me? How does she feel about me? Should I go ahead now? Oh, man! It’s like hide &amp;amp; seek game”, his mind raced with thoughts. “Will you go with me to Coonoor this weekend?” read the message. “Perfect” he blurted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nihanth is an IT guy working in Bengaluru. Kaveri is also an IT girl in the same city. He met Kaveri at a coffee house. Their bills got mixed up, and they ended up paying for each other unknowingly. While going down the staircase, he heard someone call him “Excuse me ! Mister ?”. “Nihanth” he clarified looking at her hair curls hanging on one side of her face. Her hazel eyes were hiding behind those curls. He was magnetized by her looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah Mr. Nihanth. I think our bills got mixed up, and we ended up paying for each other.” said Kaveri.
“Oh, alright! I’m in a bit of a hurry right now. Can you please ping me on my number?” 
“Yeah that’s fine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He grabbed the very first opportunity to know her number. He forgot about the coffee house incident for the rest of the day. His memory was refreshed when he got a message from her. He was ecstatic. He tried hard not to sound like a flirt. Eventually, her messages were a welcome sign to go ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They got to know better as time passed by. She appreciated his disciplined yet joyous lifestyle. He drew towards her comforting and warm persona. They hung out every weekend. They kept canceling their other plans just to meet for a couple of hours. Things started to change. They went grocery shopping together, furniture hunting together, motorcycle rides together, etc. The feelings grew. They started to care for each other. They longed for each other’s company. The weekend outings increased weekday hangouts. They were mystified about the things happening between them. He had definitely fallen in love. She too was in love. Every moment they spend with each other brings delight to their heart. Yet, they’re still perplexed what the other person felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nihanth decided he should speak his heart. He’s just waiting for an unerring occasion. But there are some questions haunting his mind. It was Thursday night. He has decided to propose that weekend. Kaveri has messaged asking to go to Coonoor. ‘Trust the timing of your life’ he thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Sure. I’m more than happy to go.”
“Great then. I’ll pick you up on Saturday early morning on my car.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He packed the best clothes he had. Although a bit skeptical, he bought a ring. Kaveri is no less enthusiastic. She had invited him hoping he would take things forward. However, she made up her mind to put an end to this dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early morning drive started with a warm hug. A long drive awaited them. He switched the car stereo on and a familiar music greeted them. ‘Tum hi ho’ started playing. They looked at each other. A deep stillness engulfed them. An empty road, early morning mist, a lovely song, and nothing but two hearts longing to get together. It had set the tone for the rest of the journey. They reached Coonoor late afternoon, taking a few breaks, talking reticently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking into the hotel, they went on local sightseeing. Nihanth was nodding off through every conversation. He was deeply engrossed in finding the perfect place and time to propose. Meanwhile, Kaveri is growing impatient with him. ‘He’s not taking things ahead. I’m sure he loves me. Should I be more subtle?’ her thoughts wandered. They were back to the hotel to get some dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What do you want to eat?” asked Nihanth.
“Two parotta and chicken curry.” replied Kaveri.
“Same for me and one Gulab jamun please.” 
“You never stop ordering that for me ! Ha-ha-ha”
“Well, you like it. There’s nothing wrong in getting what you like, right?”
“Yeah. Absolutely.”
“And by the way, what should we see tomorrow?”
“Its your call. There’re plantations here, train rides, and the Dolphin’s nose. Superb view it seems.”
“Umm. How about Catherine Falls? Its 20km from here. We’ll start early and visit the remaining places.” 
Nihanth was eyeing an undisturbed morning at the waterfalls. He smiled concealing the rush of emotions to his face.
“Alright. Sounds fun” replied a blushing Kaveri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They bid farewell after a quiet long walk on the moonlit road, with chilly winds disturbing her hair, holding hand in hand, fancying the next morning. Sleep was an enemy to both of them that night. They were excited, waiting desperately. Every passing minute felt like an year. They kept glancing at the clock every 5 minutes hoping it would skip a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was early in the morning. They started out early and reached the waterfalls. It was secluded area with not a human in sight. Nihanth immediately sat on a rock paddling his feet in the water. The fog was thick making is difficult to clearly see the top of the waterfalls. Kaveri immediately settled beside him on the same rock. She looked at him yearning to kiss his cheeks. Nihanth took out his camera to shoot the beauty of the waterfalls. An Indian redneck parrot couple sitting on a branch, hanging over the waterfalls, caught his eye. They were beautiful bright green birds pecking at each other’s neck. It felt as though they were the last remaining couple on the earth. The moment has to be seized. He immediately handed over the camera to Kaveri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked through the viewfinder and exclaimed “That’s a beautiful couple”.&lt;br /&gt;
Nihanth came closer to her left ear and whispered “Can we be that couple?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although she was expecting this, it hit her hard. She smiled. She blushed. She said “Yes”. They hugged each other. Nihanth took out the ring he brought her. Kaveri was much more surprised. She happily let him put the ring on her finger. An uncertain future has come to an end. Nihanth was beaming and grinning. He’s going to share the rest of his life with someone who loves and cares for him dearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They started their journey the next day. Its an end of a trip and a start of a beautiful life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a work of fiction.  Names, places, events, and incidents are either the products of the author’s imagination or used in a fictitious manner. Any resemblance to actual persons, living or dead, or actual events or places is purely coincidental.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cover Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@thepaintedsquare?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Jessica Lewis&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/love?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/memoirsbymp&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nihanth-kaveri/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nihanth-kaveri/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Love Story</category>
        
        
        <category>Short Story</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Voice of Pyaar Podcasted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From being mad about Hindi literature, to writing my own poems and from getting hypnotized listening to beautiful lyrics, to starting my own youtube channel, this has all been a wonderful journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Shabana and I would love to tell you about my little happenings in life that brought me the greatest happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My obsession for Hindi literature began in the early days of my schooling and within no time I became my Hindi teacher’s all-time favourite. Soon, I started listening to the lyrics of Anand Bakshi, Irshad Kamil, etc and fell in love with them. This is when my interest turned into admiration and I started writing my own poems and stories with the pseudonym “SHIDDAT”. Motivation and romance are my chosen genres of poetry. That little time I could spend for writing, during the most occupied days of my B.tech, gave me the utmost satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thereafter, Amitabh Bhattacharya’s most famous works ‘Zalima’ from Raes and the album  ‘Ae Dil Hai Mushkil’ , made me go crazy about literature and my admiration then turned into a passion. I started my own Youtube channel with my name &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCEaRP9GRiSpSwpm0yoOB3cQ&quot;&gt;SHABANA PATTAN&lt;/a&gt;. It gained around 200 subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe stories can convey even the deepest emotions. They are the signals within the noise. I hence began to share my podcasts ‘PYAAR PODCASTED, Heartfelt stories for you’ on different platforms like Spotify, Youtube, Apple Podcasts and 6 others. This is a Hindi podcast, also verified for Spotify Pitchfest and is gaining popularity consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never knew people would love my works exceedingly. And I never knew their appreciation would mean so much to me. Hope you turn up to listen to my podcast and help me keep up my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my story. If you wish to share your stories with the world, do send an email at pyaarpodcasted@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My latest podcast is live on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/4KghapZj04Smf2xvExcAMQ?si=41hIXXwrQAuFsbwcMGG3Gw&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;. It was written by Mounish Pedagandham, and turned into a podcast by me. It’s a beautiful love story of a couple struggling to express their feelings towards each other. It will be live soon on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_Follow Shabana on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCEaRP9GRiSpSwpm0yoOB3cQ&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/shiddat_._&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/1cxuf5VRAGuldET2ForkwO?si=PFozagrmRCW3zFOFNa9X2Q&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pyaar-podcasted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pyaar-podcasted/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>Experience</category>
        
        <category>Collaborations</category>
        
        <category>Stories</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In a galaxy far, far away...</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Do or do not. There is no try.”&lt;/em&gt; - Yoda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Imperial Star Destroyer intercepting Princess Leia Organa’s Tantive IV, C-3P0 and R2-D2 blabbering, the mighty Darth Vader storming into the ship angrily, and the ominous music playing in the background, all these gave me a chill down the spine. Well, there’s more ! Here are my impressions after I’ve watched the entire &lt;em&gt;Star Wars Saga&lt;/em&gt; for the first time, this April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was late to the party&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When every nerd in &lt;em&gt;The Big Bang Theory&lt;/em&gt;, a popular sit-com, was talking about the Force, quoting Yoda, playing with their Lightsabers, and having those ubiquitous cameos pushed me to the verge of finding answers to all these easter eggs. &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt;, released in 1977, changed the way children see their heroes. It was a cornerstone for this paramount of a saga. I resented for not seeing these movies earlier. Even though the original trilogy didn’t belong to my era, it was disappointing not being able to watch in on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these movies were released on Disney Plus, there was no stopping me. I read a bunch of articles to research the best order to watch the movies. Finally, I decided on a spoiler-free version, you can find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pocket-lint.com/tv/news/star-wars/147767-star-wars-machete-best-movie-viewing-order&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. A New Hope is a gem of a film, blending the action, curiosity, suspense, mystery, and a victory. The movie starts with the assault on Tantive VI, on which Princess Leia tries to escape with the plans to destroy the Galactic Empire’s secret weapon, the Death Star. She’s stopped by Darth Vader, before which she recorded a holographic message with the help of R2-D2. The R2-D2, along with C-3PO, escapes to Tatooine. A young Luke and Obi-Wan appear on the screen and try to decode Leia’s message. They set out on a journey to Alderaan, taking help from smuggler Han Solo and his first mate, a Wookiee named Chewbacca, on their ship Millenium Falcon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:47%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/3o7abL1nxw0AvOK1pu&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phew !! That’s a lot of information to take. That’s how I felt after watching the first 30 minutes of the movie. I was just pausing at every plot twist to recollect the characters. I won’t go into the plot right now, because it’s impossible to. However, I’ll go through the emotions and feelings I’ve experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Force around me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/The_Force&quot;&gt;Force&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating. An energy field that connects everything in the universe. That’s pretty novel. To those who haven’t seen the Star Wars franchise, Force is something with which a &lt;a href=&quot;https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/Force-sensitive/Legends&quot;&gt;Force-sensitive human&lt;/a&gt; can learn to sense and manipulate the Force. It is an unusual way to portray a superhero (ahem ahem !! Marvel &amp;amp; DC). One has to learn the way of force, to become a Jedi. We can witness this in &lt;em&gt;The Empire Strikes Back&lt;/em&gt;, regarded as the greatest film in the Star Wars saga. When Luke goes to Dagobah, Yoda - a highly revered guru, teaches him the ways of the force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-25-star-wars-saga/yoda.png&quot; alt=&quot;Yoda&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;Yoda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“A Jedi uses the Force for knowledge and defense, never for attack.”&lt;/em&gt; - Yoda (The Empire Strikes Back, 1980)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s exciting to see the main protagonist struggling to become a Jedi. Nevertheless, a true Jedi, adhering to the light side of the force, avoiding the emotions affiliated to the dark side of the Force. The Sith order, are driven by their emotions, like hate, anger, and greed. So, underlyingly we can see it as a battle between the good and bad virtues. The Empire Strikes Back also marks a very interesting development in the plot and the movie ends with Han Solo in a dire state. &lt;em&gt;The Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt; starts with Darth Vader landing on the more powerful Death Star. Luke and Leia attempt to rescue Han from Jabba, which backfires resulting in taking Leia as a slave, in the most famous costume of all time (if you know, you know). However, they escape from Jabba’s place and resume on their mission leading to an exciting lightsaber duel. The trilogy ends on a good note setting an interesting tone for the sequels ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three movies in the saga, colloquially known as the original trilogy or the classic trilogy, do stand up to their reputation. Making a movie in the space, in the 1970s, the use of graphics, elaborate descriptions of the planets, imagining the technology was far fetched. In my honest opinion, these were ahead of its time. However, the franchise stayed consistent of the technology used in recent movies as well. The spaceships, the nitty-gritty technical devices, etc. remain familiar, and never out of place. I am fascinated by the huge loyal fan base this franchise has earned, and I’m proud to be one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epilogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the plot progresses we feel connected to the characters, the droids, the spaceships, etc. Here is how I feel about the most prominent ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lightsabers&lt;/strong&gt;:
OMG !! They’re awesome !! The buzzing sound when it is switched on is just surreal. It engages us to watch attentively. Seeing the duel between Luke Skywalker and Darth Vader is stunning.  After watching the movie, even I tried to buy one online or make one. Rather, I was glued to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GfQVUwz1kT0&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; watching people make their own Lightsabers, in Disneyland.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:43%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/3ofSB4uhagGiWdSVbi&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every Star Wars nerd certainly loves a lightsaber ! Well, I’m no exception !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millenium Falcon&lt;/strong&gt;:
Who doesn’t love the most iconic spaceship that can do the Kessel run in less than twelve parsecs (That’s what he said (:P).) ??  It’s like home to Han Solo and Chewbacca duo. Its freakishly fast, and delivers when needed (yeah, sometimes it doesn’t).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:49%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/3ornjHyjf1FiUneGGI&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“PUNCH IT”&lt;/em&gt; - Han Solo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R2-D2&lt;/strong&gt;:
The most iconic droid of all time. Every guy wanted to own one. Cute in its own way, endurable more than one can imagine. The beeps and whistles have a sweet charm of their own. Paired with C-3PO, they make a great duo (next to Han and Chewie though!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:43%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/3ornjMd3Pu2F8Vi7DO&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whistle ! Beep ! Beep !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C-3PO&lt;/strong&gt;:
The most anxious and obedient droid on the franchise. He is unwillingly involved in the battles, and blabbers at an inappropriate time. However, he can’t survive without his counterpart R2-D2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:41%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/KGmoTveWlSxJS&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If I told you half the things I’ve heard about this Jabba the Hutt, you’d probably short circuit.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darth Vader&lt;/strong&gt;:
I didn’t want to include Darth Vader in this list. But I couldn’t help myself. He is such a strong and powerful character, that is worth mentioning. The tense situation when he appears on the screen, his heavy breathing through the helmet, his uncontrollable anger, his lightsaber duels, his force-wielding strength, all contribute to a very captivating experience, and respect towards him. He’s loved on par with those on the light side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:61%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/YMQACIPvZFZDO&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If you only knew the power of the Dark Side!”&lt;/em&gt; - Darth Vader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: Well, these are my few words on the Star Wars original trilogy. However, my impressions of the prequel and sequel trilogies, and anthology series will be out shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a bonus GIF, of my most favorite actress. (wink, wink) 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:43%;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/xTiIzRjyGBk0hqPXxK&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May the force always be with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views expressed are purely personal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photos from Google.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All GIFs &lt;a href=&quot;https://giphy.com/&quot;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below about your impressions on the Star Wars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/star-wars-org-trilogy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/star-wars-org-trilogy/</guid>
        
        <category>Star Wars</category>
        
        
        <category>Movies</category>
        
        <category>Hobbies</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Glimpse of Bengaluru</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru, crowned as the Silicon Valley of India, will make you fall in love with it instantly. Whenever the name Bengaluru is mentioned, there’s an adrenaline rush in my body. The soothing weather, lush greenery, grand buildings, the bustling traffic, the famous filter coffee (pronounced as kaapi) urges me to revisit it. I’ve had the opportunity of spending a couple of months in Bengaluru for my internship last summer (2019). Here is my first experience of Bengaluru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything New Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day I got to know that I’ll be spending the next couple of months in Bengaluru for my summer internship, there’s this wave of excitement in my body. This can probably be attributed to the stories I’ve heard, and the movies I’ve watched (the main culprit being &lt;a href=&quot;https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/malayalam/movies/news/six-years-of-bangalore-days-reasons-why-the-anjali-menons-directorial-is-a-gem/photostory/76103046.cms&quot;&gt;Bangalore Days&lt;/a&gt;). These instilled in me, an ecstasy of a dream come true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The friendship with Bengaluru started on fine Tuesday morning (21 May 2019). I was received by my cousin, who graciously offered to go PG hunting with me. I was stuck with a good deal on a twin - sharing room in RR Nagar area. We immediately set out to explore the city on his motorcycle and ended up at Cubbon Park. The first thing I noticed is the dense tree cover on either side of the road. The trees were huge, giving shade to the entire flock of motorcyclists sulking in their helmets. The second thing I noticed is the most commonly associated Bengaluru thing - the traffic. Its insanely hectic to survive the unending traffic signals, narrow lanes, continuously pestering honking. However, you’ll be greeted with a fine drizzle now and then, lightening your mood. But, it gets in your way of a conventional workday, when unprepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-22-glimpse-of-bengaluru/Snapchat-610521143.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Church Street - Bangalore&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;Church Street - Bangalore&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began exploring the city on the weekends, renting out Honda Activa from the nearby &lt;a href=&quot;https://vogo.in/&quot;&gt;Vogo&lt;/a&gt; and visited popular spots like Church Street, MG Road, Mantri Square, Orion Mall (Rajaji Nagar), ISKCON Temple, Lal Bagh Botanical Garden, and the Visvesvaraya Industrial &amp;amp; Technological Museum. I even had the initial excitement phase, to travel in the &lt;em&gt;Namma Metro&lt;/em&gt;, which subsided gradually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Namma Bengaluru Phase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-22-glimpse-of-bengaluru/IMG_20190605_172656.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lal Bagh Lake&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;Lal Bagh Lake&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After living there for a couple of months, I can say that there’s no taking away the Bangalorean in me. I got used to running into lakes (not literally though :P) all over the city, seeing exotic cars parked on the roads, the exorbitantly priced chicken sandwich, taking the weather into account before stepping out, calculating the time to reach, motorcyclists taking to the pavement, afraid of the dreaded Silk Board Signal, etc. And the vastness of the city never allows for seeing it completely. However, Bengaluru never fails to amaze me, there’s always something exciting to do in the city. The sheer number of shopping malls, restaurants, breweries, parks, etc. keep us engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weekend getaways are amazing. For instance, I visited Nandi Hills on a Saturday (that’s a story for some other day), and Chennai the other weekend. The options are endless. The phrase &lt;em&gt;Namma Bengaluru&lt;/em&gt; becomes clear, and you wholeheartedly feel belonged to the city. It makes you stay a bit longer than you planned for. As expected, I had a great time in Bengaluru. Nevertheless, the goodbyes are very hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was time for me to end the internship and get back to my college, it almost felt like leaving a brother behind. Bengaluru gave me a lot of memories to cherish, and something to look forward to in the coming days. It definitely holds a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epilogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally had a chance to fully experience the Bengaluru life this year, owing to my job posting over there. Nevertheless, it was delayed due to the restrictions at present. Having said that, I’m eagerly waiting to get out there and share my experiences with all the readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views expressed are purely personal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/prashantby/&quot;&gt;Prashanth Y&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com&quot;&gt;Flickr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All other Photos are shot by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/glimpse-of-bengaluru/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/glimpse-of-bengaluru/</guid>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Experience</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Night of the Winds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Krishna was back to his hostel from a tiring day at the University. He was still knee deep in the pile of work to be completed for his ongoing thesis. He was drained physically and mentally. But the beautiful garden, visible from his hostel room, calmed his mind instantly. The university campus, proud of its greenery, is just a few miles from the beautiful Malabar coast. A breezy twilight had set a relaxing tone for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Midnight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krishna is a very timid person. Even the thunders could scare him sometimes. He finished his work post - dinner and sat to catch a movie. He fell asleep instantly owing to a hectic day. The weather changed in an instant, from calm to chaotic. The night sky was hidden behind the mighty dark clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind started gently, and grew stronger and stronger, throwing the mighty trees side to side. The stillness of the night has been destroyed with the fierceness of the mighty northeast winds. The banging doors and rattling windows woke him up. The howling wind sound filled his mind with uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He immediately shut the windows closed and grabbed his earplugs. Despite their effort, they could do nothing to stop the hooting of the wind from reaching his heart. The window panes rattled against the rushing winds instilled fear in his heart. The doors fought with the mightiness of the winds holding on to their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was wide awake by then. His mind, waiting for the rain to come upon the ravaging wind, wandered off into a perpetual void. The howls of the street dogs further contributed to the eeriness of the night, giving him chills down the spine. His body was begging him to sleep. But the constant whispers of the wind disturbed his mind not letting it rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- image here  --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-20-windy-night/pan-xiaozhen-OKlo0r3gBcQ-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by pan xiaozhen on Unsplash&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;Photo by pan xiaozhen on Unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heavy clouds finally gave in to a torrential downpour. The rain brought a relief, to his anxious mind, that he thought existed. Tears of joy rolled down his cheeks, putting his tormented mind to sleep. The incessant patter of the rain has been a music to his ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It brought a smile to his face, finally letting him sleep peacefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a work of fiction.  Names, places, events, and incidents are either the products of the author’s imagination or used in a fictitious manner. Any resemblance to actual persons, living or dead, or actual events or places is purely coincidental.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/users/StockSnap-894430/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;amp;utm_content=2589417&quot;&gt;StockSnap&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;amp;utm_content=2589417&quot;&gt;Pixabay.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Rain Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@zhenhappy?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;pan xiaozhen&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/windy-night/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/windy-night/</guid>
        
        <category>Thoughts</category>
        
        
        <category>Short Story</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is the ban on Chinese Apps sufficient to be Aatm Nirbhar?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst the growing tensions between India and China on the military front, the government of India announced the ban of 59 mobile apps stating that they are ‘prejudicial to sovereignty, integrity, defense of India, the security of the state and public order’ invoking the power under Section 69A of the IT Act ( provisions of IT Rules 2009).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does Aatm Nirbhar mean?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Honourable Prime Minister Shri Narendra Modi, announced the special economic package on May 12 to uplift India’s economy desecrated by the national wide lockdown due to the ongoing pandemic caused by COVID — 19. The package aims to make India independent from foreign competition in the global supply chain and empower the underprivileged affected by the lockdown. The phrase Aatm Nirbhar means to be self-dependent, which can be collocated to the self-sufficient production of goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does it resonate with the current context?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- image here  --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-1-aatm-nirbhar/chuttersnap-unsplash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo by chuttersnap on Unsplash&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;Photo by chuttersnap on Unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present situation with China at the LAC possess a challenging situation for India. The loss of lives of 20 Indian soldiers during the clash between the Indian Army and PLA at the Galwan valley on June 15 sent an alarming manifestation of the arduous situation at the LAC. A delayed and ambiguous response had paved for ominous remarks, although later clarified it left stifling unrest in the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To brush away the propaganda, nationwide dissension against the use of Chinese products was brought forth. This ‘boycott Chinese products’ motto worked well in the likes of political executives. To further consolidate the outcry, an agenda for a self-reliant India free from the shackles of China has been bestowed. Thus, an Aatm Nirbhar India has to be accomplished sooner or later, essentially with respect to China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can India boycott China?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact of India not continuing trade with China torments the former’s economy. China is one of the largest trading partners with India with an estimate of $16.34 billion in exports and $68.06 billion in imports for FY17. The imports from China had considerably decreased by 15% from the FY18 due to anti-dumping duties, and the number stands at $65.1 billion for FY20. However, the exports have gained a minuscule percentage and stand at $16.6 billion for FY20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dependence of Indian automobile, pharmaceutical industries on the raw materials, available at low cost, from China possess a problem to boycott the Chinese products. Over a quarter of India’s auto parts imports have come from China in 2019 amounting to $4.2 billion. These are crucial parts in the manufacturing process, without which the development of costly alternatives aggravates the local business and profits, says the automobile manufacturing groups. “The imports from China directly contribute to over 30% of India’s aggregate trade deficit.” says Suman Chowdhury, from Acuité Ratings &amp;amp; Research. Thus, the dependence of the domestic economy on imports from China is quite significant.
The report by S&amp;amp;P Global Ratings on 26 June predicts that the Indian economy is in deep trouble, with difficulty in containing the virus, its growth is expected to fall by 5% this fiscal. With such a taxing scenario on the business front, India cannot immediately cut the trading ties with its Asian business partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ban of Chinese mobile apps, though a welcoming step, it serves a diminutive effect on the ongoing bilateral issues and the trade between the two nations. However, further steps are, and should be, under consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Feasible Foresight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- image here  --&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post_images/2020-07-1-aatm-nirbhar/foresight.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align: center;
    color:grey; 
    font-size: smaller; margin-top:4px&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is trying to stiffen the curbs on 1,173 non-essential imports, through dialogue with companies, mentions a trading body in India. Furthermore, the customs scrutiny of the exports at the Chennai port has deliberately been intensified leading to delay in the delivery of goods. This move had a contemplated repercussion on the Chinese side of exports to India, leading to delays, worrying the importing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the study by Acuité Research &amp;amp; Rating shows that India can potentially reduce its trade deficit with China by $8.4 billion over FY21–22, which is equivalent to 17.3% of the deficit with China and 0.3% of India’s GDP, further leading to self-reliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This notion of the boycott cannot be achieved overnight. It would hurt the Indians dependent on logistic supply chains if a sudden boycott should be imposed. It takes a pragmatic approach and careful planning of foreign and trade policies not only with China, but also other trading partners i.e. the government should frame the policies aiming to reduce the dependence of the economy not only on Chinese products, but also other foreign products. The self reliability should be achieved in strategic financial sectors to be free from external market players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, this pandemic proved that we have to be Aatm Nirbhar to sustain our Pharma, Automobile, Agri, manufacturing industries. We, as people, have to be ‘vocal for local’ as endorsed by Hon’ble Prime Minister. Hence, India should strive to stand up not only against China, but against all foreign competition to progress as a prosperous nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.  .  .&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The information presented above is from various sources like Wikipedia, The Hindu.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The views expressed are purely personal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@naveedahmed?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Naveed Ahmed&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/india-china?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash.&lt;/a&gt;
Second Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@chuttersnap?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;chuttersnap&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@chuttersnap?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please do&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;subscribe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;to my newsletter, and leave a&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;comment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/aatm-nirbhar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/aatm-nirbhar/</guid>
        
        <category>India - China</category>
        
        
        <category>Current Affairs</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
